Just like how Python has libraries that make Python development easier,
就像 Python 拥有使 Python 开发更容易的库一样
there are libraries built on top of CSS and
也有基于 CSS 和 JavaScript
JavaScript that make web development much easier.
使 Web 开发更容易的库
From this point on in the lesson,
从课程这一部分开始
you'll only need to write HTML,
你只需要编写 HTML
Python, and a little bit of JavaScript.
Python 还有一点 JavaScript
But behind the scenes,
但在幕后
libraries will be taken care of the CSS and most of the JavaScript for you.
库将为你处理 CSS 和大多数 JavaScript
First, let me remind you of the goal.
首先提醒一下你的目标
You want to get a front-end that looks like this.
你要完成一个看起来像这样的前端
In this video, I'm going to build up this front-end for you so you can see how I did it,
这个视频中 我将构建此前端 帮助你了解如何去做
and then you can practice doing it yourself in the exercise.
然后你可以在练习中自己实践
For now, in this video,
在这个视频中
I'm just going to use images for the visualizations rather than
我只会使用图片作为可视化内容
the HTML visualizations that you're going to make later in the lesson.
而不是你将在本课后面构建的 HTML 可视化
To make this front-end,
要构建这个前端
I use the Bootstrap library.
我使用 Bootstrap 库
This is the Bootstrap homepage.
这是 Bootstrap 主页
The Bootstrap documentation is pretty good.
Bootstrap 的文档非常好
There are many examples,
有很多例子
and each example comes with code.
每个例子都带有代码
Oftentimes, you can just copy and paste the example code
通常 你只需在网站上复制粘贴示例代码
from their website and then change the content to fit your needs.
然后根据自己需求修改内容
That's exactly what I'm going to do here.
这正是我即将操作的
Going back to their homepage,
回到他们的主页
I'm going to click on their Get started button.
我要点击 Get started 按钮
So, here on this page,
在这个页面上
there's actually a template that you can copy and paste as a starter.
实际上有一个可供复制粘贴的入门模板
That's exactly what I'm going to do here.
这正是我要在这里做的操作
I'm going to copy and paste their starter code template.
我要复制并粘贴入门代码模板
So far, it doesn't look like much.
目前为止 看起来内容并不多
It just says, "Hello, world!"
只是写了 Hello, world!
But let me explain what all of this code is.
不过让我解释一下 所有这些代码的意思
First of all, you have a doctype tag like what we discussed before,
首先 有一个我们之前讨论过的 doctype 标签
and then there's the HTML tag and it specifies
然后是 html 标签
in this case that the language of the website is English.
在这个示例中 指定了网站的语言是英语
In the head tag, we've got things like these meta tags and then links.
在 head 标签中 有一些 meta 和 link 标签
So, the first meta tag is just notifying the browser that the character set is utf-8,
第一个 meta 标签只是通知浏览器字符集是 utf-8
and then the viewport meta tag is for
然后 viewport meta 标签是用来设置
shrinking and expanding the content for web versus mobile.
根据网络设备缩小和放大内容
Then, there's a link to the Bootstrap CSS library,
然后有一个指向 Bootstrap CSS 库的链接
then we have the title "Hello, world!",
然后页面标题是 Hello, world!
then the body starts where the bulk of your HTML content goes.
然后是 body 标签以及大部分的 HTML 内容
Then, we have these links to all of these JavaScript scripts,
然后是指向所有 JavaScript 脚本的链接
and these are linking to jQuery essentially.
本质上是链接到 jQuery
Bootstrap uses jQuery to do some of its animations.
Bootstrap 使用 jQuery 来完成一些动画
The essential trick to using Bootstrap is that the screen is
使用 Bootstrap 的基本技巧
divided into these invisible rows and 12 columns.
就是将屏幕划分为不可见的行和 12 列
You can have as many rows as you want.
你可以拥有任意数量的行
Behind the scenes, Bootstrap is going to use CSS to make the layout happen for you,
在幕后 Bootstrap 使用 CSS 进行布局
and all you have to do is specify IDs and classes.
你需要做的就是指定 id 和 class
All of this is spelled out pretty explicitly in the documentation for Bootstrap.
所有这些都在 Bootstrap 文档中有明确说明
I'm going to show you a quick example of what all of these rows and columns look like.
我将快速展示一些示例 看看这些行和列的外在表现
So, I'm going to erase this "Hello, world!"
删除这里的 Hello, world!
here, and then I'm going to add a div and give it the class of row,
然后添加一个 div 并将其设置为 class="row"
and then close that div.
然后关闭 div
Inside of this row,
在这个 row 中
I'm going to make a class called column-1 or col-1,
我要创建一个名为 col-1 的列
and then we close this tag.
然后关闭这个标签
I'm just going to write here C1.
在这里只写一个 C1
So, we have this column here, C1.
那么这里就显示出了这个列 (column) C1
I'm going to just copy and paste this so that there are 12 of them.
复制粘贴 制作 12 个列
So, hopefully, this makes it clear that this row
希望这样可以清楚地表明
is divided into 12 evenly spaced sections.
这一行被划分为 12 个均匀间隔的部分
Now, I'm going to make another row,
现在再制作一行
and I'm just going to copy all of this again.
只需要再次复制这些
So, now I have a second row with 12 evenly spaced columns.
现在有第二行了 也是 12 个均匀间隔的列
So, you have these 12 divisions to work with,
这样你就有 12 个 div 可以使用了
but you don't need to use all 12.
不过你也不用全部都划分为 12 个
For example, I can say this first one is just four across and then the next one is eight,
比如 第一个可以设置为 4 下一个是 8
and then I'm going to erase all the rest of the ones.
然后删除其他
So, now you have a row that has one column that has
那么现在这行就变成了有一列
four spaces and then one column that has eight spaces.
占 4 个空位 另一列占 8 个空位
So, for this next one, just to give another example,
对于下一行 再举个例子
I'm going to give this seven and the next one five,
给第一列 7  第二列 5
and still everything adds up to 12 divisions,
相加仍然等于 12
but you can see here on the right that
你可以在右边看到
the first part has seven divisions and the second part has five divisions.
第一部分有 7 个空位 第二部分有 5 个空位
So, you can use these rows and columns to divide up the screen in any way you want to.
你可以使用这些 row 和 col 以任何你需要的方式划分屏幕
If you go back to my web app,
返回看我的 Web 应用
you can see perhaps how I've divided this up.
你应该可以看出 我是如何划分的
So, this section on the bottom is just one big row,
底部的部分就是一个大的行
and then I've divided that row into a column
然后我将该行分成了
of width one and another column here of width 11.
一个宽度为 1 的列以及另一个宽度为 11 的列
Then, I've made another row within a column that has two columns,
然后我在后一列创建了另一行 其中划分为两列
and then I made another row that also has two columns.
然后又创建了一行 也有两列
I'm going to show you how this works with code as well.
我来展示一下如何使用代码
But let's build this up starting from
不过 我们从顶部开始构建
the top with the navigation bar and then working our way down.
也就是导航栏的位置 然后再向下继续工作
I'm here back at the Bootstrap homepage.
现在回到 Bootstrap 主页
I'm going to click on Documentation,
点击文档
and then here I'm just going to search for navbar.
然后在这里 我只需要搜索导航栏
So, on this page, there are a bunch of examples of how to make a navbar.
这个页面上 有很多关于如何制作导航栏的例子
So, all I did was I saw this one, I liked it,
我所做的就是 看到了这个 觉得很喜欢
I copied this code,
就复制了这段代码
and then I paste it into my HTML.
然后我将其粘贴到我的 HTML 中
I'm going to erase all of this stuff on
我要删除所有底部的东西
the bottom just so that it's easier to see what we're doing,
为了更容易看到正在做的事情
and I'm going to change the website title to Data Dashboard.
我要将网站标题更改为 Data Dashboard
So, this navbar is pretty similar to the one that I have in my web app,
这个导航栏与我的 Web 应用中的导航栏非常相似
but the colors are a little different,
只是颜色有点不同
the links are a little different.
链接有点不同
So, all I have to do is just change those things.
所以我所要做的就是修改这些东西
So, to change the color, for example,
假设说要修改颜色
this says navbar-light here as a class,
这里显示了 navbar-light 类名
and I'm going to say navbar-dark.
我将其修改为 navbar-dark
This bg-light stands for background light,
这个 bg-light 代表浅色背景
I'm going to change to background dark.
我要修改为深色背景
So, this is already looking more like the web page I have.
这样看起来更像我的网页了
Now, how did I know to change these classes?
那么我要如何知道 需要修改哪些类呢?
Well, it's all in the documentation.
嗯 都在文档里
So, it shows you that you can change
文档中展示了 你可以修改
the navbar color and you can change the navbar shading using these different classes.
导航栏颜色 你也可以使用这些不同的类修改导航栏背景
Here, I put World Bank Data Dashboard,
这里我修改为 World Bank Data Dashboard
and then we also need to change these links here.
然后还需要修改这里的链接
So, the links are actually here in this HTML list.
链接实际上在这个 HTML 列表中
I'm going to say this first one is a link to the Udacity website,
我想设置的第一个 是优达学城网站的链接
and so I need to change the h reference here to udacity.com,
所以我需要将 href 修改为 udacity.com
and then it has this span element in here that I don't actually want.
然后这里有一个 span 元素 我实际上并不想要
So I'm going to delete that. So, we have this first one.
所以删除它 这样我们有第一个链接了
Did you notice as well in this list here it says class="nav-item active"?
你是否也注意到此列表中的 class ="nav-item active"？
I don't particularly want that,
我不是特别想要这个效果
and that got rid of the white highlighting that it had.
删除之后去掉了原来的白色高亮显示
Now, I wanted to link to the World Bank Data.
现在 我想链接到世界银行数据
So, that showed up. Now, this pricing and disabled,
设置好了 现在这个 pricing 和 disabled
we're not actually using, so we can delete them.
我们实际上没有用到 所以可以删除
Here we delete pricing,
这里删除 pricing
here we delete disabled,
这里删除 disabled
and this is looking pretty good.
看起来很不错
I'm going to expand this
我要放大一点
a little bit because that's the mobile view and this is the desktop view.
因为之前是移动视图 这才是桌面视图
So, actually, there is a little bit of a difference.
实际上还有一点不同
This was right-aligned on my app,
我的应用中 这些是右对齐的
and here it's actually left-aligned.
而这里实际上是左对齐的
So, how can we change that?
那么怎样才能改变呢?
If you look it up in the documentation,
如果在文档中查找
you will find that if you add a margin with margin-left auto,
会发现只需要添加一个外边距 ml-auto (ml 是指 maigin left)
you can actually change that.
就可以改变了
So, I'm going to add that into my code.
所以 我将这个类添加到代码中
You can see that it changed the alignment for me.
你可以看到它改变了对齐方式
Again, so the great thing about this library is
再次强调 这个库的伟大之处在于
that you just have to change the classes and IDs in all of your tags,
你只需要修改所有标签中的 class 和 id
and the CSS just gets taken care of for you.
CSS 就会对应更改
So, let's go back to the app.
我们回到应用
Like I said before, this bottom part here is made by nesting columns and rows together.
就像我之前说过的 这里的底部将列和行嵌套在一起
So, I personally like to first write out the structure
我个人喜欢先将行列的结构写出来
with all of the rows and columns and then fill those in. You don't have to do it.
然后再填充内容 不过这不是必须的要求
You can build it up little by little,
你可以一点一点地构建
but here's how I do it.
这是我完成的步骤
So, down here, I know that I want everything to be inside of a row.
在这里 我知道我想要一切都在一行中
Then, inside that row,
然后 在这一行中
I have a column of width one and I have
有一个宽度为 1 的列
another column of width 11 to fill out the rest of the space.
以及另一个宽度为 11 的列 填充剩下的空间
Looking back at the dashboard, this is fine.
回顾一下仪表板 这样不错
We'll be able to do this now.
我们现在可以做到这一点
This part in here actually has a row here and then another row,
这部分上面有一行 然后下面是另一行
and each of these rows have two columns. So, let's put that in.
并且每个行都有两列 那么我们把这些放进去
We can add another row and another row.
我们可以添加一行和另一行
Then, within that row,
然后在这一行内
I'm going to put two columns each of width six,
我要放两个宽度为 6 的列
and then I'm just going to copy and paste this.
然后就可以复制粘贴
So, that's essentially the skeleton of the bottom part.
所以这就是底部的基础骨架
So now, it's just a matter of filling things in.
现在只是填充内容的问题了
So, for this left-hand column,
对于这个左侧边栏
I am going to add links to LinkedIn and GitHub.
我要添加 LinkedIn 和 GitHub 的链接
So, here in href is where,
这里的 href 是指向哪里
say, you would put a link to your LinkedIn profile.
假设你会添加一个自己的 LinkedIn 个人资料页链接
Then, in the assets folder that you can see here on the left,
在左侧可以看到的 assets 资源文件夹中
I have put in a bunch of images,
我放了一些图片
and I'm going to put those images into the web page.
我要把这些图片放到网页上
Specify an alt tag and close the link.
指定 alt 标记然后关闭链接
Now, let's put in GitHub,
现在放入 GitHub
and this is where you could put in the link to your GitHub profile in the href attribute.
你可以在 href 属性中放入指向 GitHub 个人资料的链接
So, these images are pretty large and they're also touching each other,
这些图片非常大 还紧挨在一起
which is not exactly how I had it in the web app.
这并不是我在 Web 应用中的显示方式
So, in the documentation,
在文档中
you'll see that there's a class called img-fluid that will
你会看到有一个名为 img-fluid 的类
actually make these images shrink and expand in a nicer way.
可以使这些图片缩小并以更好的方式扩展
So, I'm going to add that class here.
所以我将在这里添加该类
Now, you can see that these images grow and shrink with the size of the web page.
现在可以看到这些图片随着网页的大小而放大和缩小
I'm also going to add a couple of other things.
我还要添加一些其他设置
For example, I put a border
比如在右侧放置一个边框
here on the right-hand side which I can add with the border-right class.
我可以添加一个 border-right 类
It shows up right here.
这里出现了
When the website is a little larger,
网站稍微大一点时
you'll be able to see it better in a second.
你可以更容易看到它
I'm also just going to add an extra div here on top.
我要在上面添加一个额外的 div
I'm going to add a class called mt-3;
添加一个名为 mt-3 的类
mt stands for margin top,
mt 表示 margin top 外边距顶部
and the -3 means that I want to add a margin of three.
而 -3 表示我想给外边距增加 3
So, let's see what that looks like. It's getting better.
我们来看看它是什么样的 越来越好了
So, I also added a little bit of space between these images,
我还在这些图片之间添加了一点空间
and I added a little bit of margin to the left of these images. So, let's do that.
在这些图片的左边添加了一点外边距 来加一下
Here, I added a little bit of top margin to this image of the GitHub icon,
在这里 我为这张 GitHub 图标添加了一点上边距
and I'm going to add a little bit of left margin,
然后要添加一点左边距
and then I'm going to go into the LinkedIn class
然后进入 LinkedIn 类
here and also add in a little bit of left margin.
也添加一点左边距
So this is looking a lot better.
看起来好多了
So, let's look at the web app one more time.
我们再看一次 Web 应用
So, we have these headers up here on top,
在这里有这些标题
the World Bank Data Dashboard: Top 10 World Economies Land Use,
World Bank Data Dashboard: Top 10 World Economies Land Use
and then we have these four visualization.
然后有这四个可视化
So, let's finish that up.
我们来完成它
This is in the column 11 class.
这是在 col-11 的列中
So, here at the very top,
在最顶端
I am going to add a h2 header,
我要添加一个 h2 标题
and I'm going to call it World Bank Data Dashboard.
设置为 World Bank Data Dashboard
Then I had an h4 header below it,
然后在它下面有一个 h4 标题
and I said Top 10 World Economies Land Use and then close that tag.
设置为 Top 10 World Economies Land Use 然后关闭标签
Now, this looks a little bit different because I made this a gray color.
现在看起来有点不同 因为我把它变成了灰色
Again, in the documentation,
再次到文档中查找
it talks about the classes you need to use to change the color.
其中介绍了改变颜色你需要用的类
In this case, the class I used was called text-muted.
在这个示例中 我使用的类名是 text-muted
We're looking good, we're getting close.
看起来很好 比较接近了
Now, it's just a matter of filling in
现在只需要在每个部分填充对应的可视化图表
So here, I specify that the image should be fluid,
这里我指定图片应该是 img-fluid 的
and then I specify the actual image.
然后指定实际的图片
Let's see how that looks.
看看怎么样
Now, I'm just going to copy and paste this and put it into
现在 我只需要复制粘贴这些代码
the next column and change the name of the file to plot2,
放入下一列 将图片名称修改为 plot2
and then I'm going to add the next image and call that plot3,
然后添加下一个图片 修改为 plot3
then I'm just going to copy in the code for
然后就要复制最后的图片了
the final image and call that plot4, and that is it.
将其修改为 plot4 就是这样了
Now, we have something that looks pretty similar to the web app up here.
现在 我们看到的内容与此处的 Web 应用非常相似
That's how I built the front-end for this web app.
这就是我为这个 Web 应用构建前端的方式
The only thing left is to put an actual HTML,
唯一剩下的就是放入真正的 HTML
JavaScript visualizations rather than just using images,
JavaScript 可视化而不仅仅是使用图片
and you're going to do that with the Plotly library.
你会用 Plotly 库来做到这一点
But before getting into the Plotly library,
但在进入 Plotly 库的学习之前
there's an exercise for you to practice using Bootstrap.
需要先完成 Bootstrap 的练习